









Citizenship: Cypriot (EU), British Overseas & Turkish 10823 Berlin

ABOUT

I am a data scientist specializing in psychometrics, psycholinguistics, and modeling subjectivity. My passion is revealing and understanding heterogeneity. That translates into various unsupervised machine learning and natural language processing applications like latent profile analysis, latent class analysis, psychological profiles with psychometric networks, semantic networks, concept class analysis.

SKILLS

Data Science

Proficient with

pandas, numpy, scikit-learn, matplotlib, seaborn tidyverse, tidymodels, tidyflow, easystats, lavaan (& its ecosystem), psychometric networks (collection of packages), quanteda (& its ecosystem), spacy Familiar with

Tensorflow-Keras, pytorch, prophet

Programming

Proficient with Git, Bash

Databases

Familiar with

Postgres, SQLite, MongoDB

Deployment

Familiar with

AWS (EC2, RDS), Docker, Flask

EDUCATION

2021	Data Science Bootcamp
	Spiced Academy, Berlin, Germany
2015 - 2018	Ph.D. in Political Science
	CvO Universität Oldenburg,
	Oldenburg, Germany
2008 - 2012	M.A. in Political Science
	Bilkent University, Ankara, Turkey
2005 - 2008	M.A. in International Relations
	Galatasaray University, Istanbul,
	Turkey
1999 - 2004	B.A. in International Relations
	Istanbul Bilgi University, Istanbul,
	Turkey

SELECTED PROJECTS

Measuring Organizational Practices

Natural language processing

Movie Recommender

O Unsupervised machine learning

Image Classification with Deep Learning

C Deep learning

Dockerized Data Pipeline

🚺 Involves: MongoDB, ETL job (sentiment analysis), Postgres & Slackbot

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

02-11/2020 Postdoctoral Fellow

Jacobs University, Bremen,

Germany

Worked as the lead data analyst in a third-party funded project (Business Finland & Hofstede Insights) developing a dictionary that measures organizational culture with Hofstede's Multi-Focus Model

Used the R tidy ecosystem; the quanteda ecosystem (including spacyr), rJST, tidytext, sentimentr & the easystats ecosystem

Affiliated Postdoctoral Since 02/2019

Fellow

Bremen International School of Social Sciences, Bremen,

Germany

Conducting research, publishing academic papers, teaching methods classes

01/2019 - 02/2020 (Interim-) Academic

Coordinator

CvO Universität Oldenburg,

Oldenburg, Germany

07/2012 - 07/2018 **Research Assistant Lecturer**

CvO Universität Oldenburg,

Oldenburg, Germany

LANGUAGES

Turkish (Native), English (Proficient), German (Intermediate)